Born into Wealth. Groomed by the Elite. Trained for Combat.
Lara Croft: Tomb Raider is a adventure, action,
fantasy film directed by Simon West.
Orphaned heiress, English aristocrat and intrepid archaeologist, Lara Croft, embarks on a dangerous quest to
retrieve the two halves of an ancient artifact which controls time before it falls into the wrong hands.
As an extremely rare planetary alignment is about to occur for the first time in 5,000 years, the fearless tomb raider will
have to team up with rival adventurers and sworn enemies to collect the pieces, while time is running out.
But, in the end, who can harness the archaic talisman's unlimited power?
Lara Croft, played by Angelina Jolie.
Manfred Powell, played by Iain Glen.
Alex West, played by Daniel Craig.
Bryce, played by Noah Taylor.
Hillary, played by Chris Barrie.
Lord Richard Croft, played by Jon Voight.
Lara Croft: Tomb Raider – The Cradle of Life is a 2003 action adventure film
directed by Jan de Bont and based on the Tomb Raider video game series.
Angelina Jolie stars as the title character Lara Croft with supporting performances from Gerard Butler,
Ciarán Hinds, Chris Barrie, Noah Taylor, Til Schweiger, Djimon Hounsou, and Simon Yam.
An international co-production between the United States, United Kingdom, Germany, Hong Kong
and Japan, the film is a sequel to the 2001 film Lara Croft: Tomb Raider.
Critics considered The Cradle of Life to be better than its predecessor, especially in
terms of its action sequences, and continued to praise Jolie's performance.
The film did not achieve the same level of box office success as the previous
installment, grossing $160.1 million compared to its predecessor's $275 million.
Initially, plans were made for a sequel, but these plans were
abandoned when Jolie decided not to return as Croft.
A reboot of the series, simply titled Tomb Raider, was released in
2018 with Alicia Vikander taking over the title role.
The Cradle of Life also marks the final film directed by
De Bont before his retirement in 2012.
The film explores themes of london, england, buddhist monk,
planetary alignment, angkor wat, illuminati.